#### Overview

With a background in Computer Science and more than twenty years developing for the web, I have experience with numerous technologies. Self-motivated and efficient, I am capable of taking on multiple projects and producing impressive results. A creative problem-solver and eager to learn, I would be a valuable asset to any development team. I am looking for a challenging and fulfilling position which allows me to put my abilities to good use and encourages professional growth.

## **Drupal Development Experience**

- Experience with Drupal 6, 7, and 8
- Usage of Content Types, Views and Blocks
- · Probably more experience with User Roles, Workflow, and Content Moderation than most people think is necessary
- · As developer, have almost always ended up doing administration including maintenance, updates, backups, and security
- · Extensive use of hooks in custom modules
- Have built and debugged numerous custom themes in both Drupal 7 and 8
- Attended multiple DrupalCons with delight
- · Recent projects have included
  - System to aggregate items from multiple XML feeds, allow a user to curate imported items, send HTML email of selected items
  - o Digital publishing for small newspaper
  - o "Starterkit" to build new/standardized sites quickly
  - o So many higher ed websites I cannot count

# Web Development Experience

- Front End
  - o Proficient with HTML5 and CSS3
  - Heavy SASS/SCSS usage
  - o Trying to keep up with Bootstrap
  - Usage of Pattern Lab and atomic design for consistent branding
  - o Extensive use of JavaScript, jQuery and jQuery UI
    - Forms, slideshows, menus and navigation
  - Numerous implementations of responsive design
    - Media queries, JavaScript, AJAX and PHP
    - Multiple devices, varying complexities and content
- Back End
  - o Development with WordPress
    - Custom functionality and Post types
    - Page templates and themes
    - Security
  - o Familiarty with social networking APIs
  - o Handy with XML but prefer JSON
  - o SEO friendly
- DevOps
  - o Advocate for Dev/Test/Live production environments
  - Enthusiastic about documentation and version control
  - o A bajillion years of experience with LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP)

1 of 2

# **Work History**

### Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, January 2018 to present

- RPI is an internationally recognized research institute with a focus on engineering, advanced materials, and artificial
  intelligence. Very small web team, of which I was the only developer, needs to support dozens of websites for various existing
  and new projects.
- Recent wins have included removing or replacing Drupal 6 sites, keeping Drupal 7 and 8 sites up-to-date, developing a
  "starterkit" to make it easier to quickly "spin up" consistently on-brand, accessible, mobile-friendly websites, and
  documentation for my own sanity.

### Overit Media, March 2013 to December 2016, Web Developer

- Overit Media is a digital marketing firm. The small development team worked closely with design and strategy teams to build
  everything from small websites for brochures and event promotion to incredibly complicated suites of software to support
  thousands of users.
- Responsibilities included back-end implementation using WordPress or Drupal, and front-end development using HTML5,
   CSS3, jQuery and responsive web design techniques. Additionally, regular maintenance and support was provided for projects,
   which included upgrading core and plugins, performance improvements and debugging end-user issues.
- Many recent projects required massive amounts of custom module development for Drupal 8.

### Zone 5, May 2008 to February 2013, Web Developer

- Zone 5 is a marketing and communications agency. Their Web Services group is a small team helping to develop solutions for higher education, healthcare, and technology industries.
- Projects ranged from on-line viewbooks that integrate with social media, to massive applications that allow users to apply for technical certification. Many projects involved working with designers and front end implementation, using existing APIs and libraries, and developing custom functionality.

MountainMedia.com, Inc, February 2007 to April 2008, PHP Developer and System Administrator

HostRocket.com, Inc, June 2006 to January 2007, PHP Developer

Eden Communications, Inc, August 2004 to April 2006, Lotus Notes Developer

First Albany Corporation, May 2001 to August 2003, Application Developer

Marist College, June 1999 to February 2001, Application Developer

### Education

Bachelor's of Science in Computer Science from Marist College (1999) Studied software development lifecycle, algorithms, object oriented programming, compiler design, database design, etc. Used Java for many major projects.

2 of 2